Christopher Goodwin

User Experience Developer

802-540-5036 hello@christophergoodwin.me christophergoodwin.me linkedin.com/in/goodwinc

About

I believe in building a web that works for everyone, everywhere. Using primarily HTML & CSS, I write performant and maintainable code that's fast, responsive, and accessible.

I've had the privilege of building world class web experiences with companies such as Apple, Netflix, CIEE, and Sparta Science.

Experience

Senior User Experience Developer at DockYard

2016 - Present

- Leading UX development on web apps with companies such as Apple, Netflix, and Sparta Science
- · Working collaboratively with team members to translate designs into semantic, reliable code
- Writing and auditing code to ensure accessibility, performance, and graceful degradation
- Refining code standards and growing company understanding of UX best practices
- · Mentoring colleagues seeking improvement in their front-end skills
- · Maintaining and implementing inclusive hiring practices
- · Co-working remotely with a fully distributed team

Front End Web Developer at Council on International Education Exchange

2014 - 2016

- Worked with a team to design and develop responsive and accessible websites
- · Estimated timelines and scoped work to meet project deadlines
- · Maintained and updated over 20 marketing websites

Freelance Web Developer

2011 - 2014

- · Designed, developed, and maintained corporate and personal websites
- · Spent time with clients to learn about their needs and helped to grow their brands
- Trained clients to update and maintain their sites for long term use

Skills

HTML and CSS expertise with focus on semantic, maintainable code

- Robust understanding of accessibility best practices
- Design experience and familiarity with modern design software
- Experience building and maintaining design systems and component libraries
- · Background in Javascript development
- Strong knowledge of Git and version control
- Adept at working remotely
- Photography and video production background

Education

BS with Web and Interactive Media focus

Pennsylvania College of Technology
The Art Institute of New England
2010 - 2011

Certificate of Completion

Center for Technology, Essex
2008 - 2010